<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Camping Aizier</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Camping Aizier</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hunchback of Notre Dame</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame/</guid>
      <description>In the vaulted Gothic towers of Notre-Dame Cathedral lives Quasimodo, the hunchbacked bellringer. Mocked and shunned for his appearance, he is pitied only by Esmerelda, a beautiful gypsy dancer to whom he becomes completely devoted. Esmerelda, however, has also attracted the attention of the sinister archdeacon Claude Frollo, and when she rejects his lecherous approaches, Frollo hatches a plot to destroy her, that only Quasimodo can prevent. Victor Hugo&amp;rsquo;s sensational, evocative novel brings life to the medieval Paris he loved, and mourns its passing in one of the greatest historical romances of the nineteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting the French Revolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/interpreting-the-french-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/interpreting-the-french-revolution/</guid>
      <description>The French Revolution is an historical event unlike any other. It is more than just a topic of intellectual interest: it has become part of a moral and political heritage. But after two centuries, this central event in French history has usually been thought of in much the same terms as it was by its contemporaries. There have been many accounts of the French Revolution, and though their opinions differ, they have often been commemorative or anniversary interpretations of the original event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ancien Régime and the Revolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/the-ancien-r%C3%A9gime-and-the-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/the-ancien-r%C3%A9gime-and-the-revolution/</guid>
      <description>The Ancien Régime and the Revolution is a comparison of revolutionary France and the despotic rule it toppled. Alexis de Tocqueville (1805–59) is an objective observer of both periods – providing a merciless critique of the ancien régime, with its venality, oppression and inequality, yet acknowledging the reforms introduced under Louis XVI, and claiming that the post-Revolution state was in many ways as tyrannical as that of the King; its once lofty and egalitarian ideals corrupted and forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Les Misérables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/books/les-mis%C3%A9rables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/books/les-mis%C3%A9rables/</guid>
      <description>Introducing one of the most famous characters in literature, Jean Valjean—the noble peasant imprisoned for stealing a loaf of bread—Les Misérables ranks among the greatest novels of all time. In it, Victor Hugo takes readers deep into the Parisian underworld, immerses them in a battle between good and evil, and carries them to the barricades during the uprising of 1832 with a breathtaking realism that is unsurpassed in modern prose.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
